## Dear Remind,

I would like to apply for the Javascript Engineering and Backend/Infrastructure roles at Remind, whose openings I have learned of through Jobmine.

Currently, I am pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering at the University of Waterloo, and will be graduating in the year of 2018. In my most recent internship, I worked for Ten Thousand Coffees to push high impact code into production, working on a variety of core features using Node, Angular, and MongoDB; writing RESTful compliant API's as well as Mocha unit tests. I am also currently working on several side projects: Chidori, an Yugioh client built with Electron and React, as well as Hearthnet, which is a web application built with Meteor. Finally, I am also currently working as a freelance web developer for Write of Passage on the side, while doing my studies this term.

Enclosed in this email is my resume. If you feel that I am a befitting candidate for the Javascript Engineering or Backend/Infracstructure roles at Remind, please don't hesitate to contact me! Thank you for your time, and I look forward to your response.

Sincerely, Clement Hoang

# Clement Hoang

**6**47 871 8336

☑ c8hoang@uwaterloo.ca

https://github.com/clemmy

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/clementhoang

◆ http://clemmy.ninja

## Skills

[Languages] Javascript, HTML/CSS, Java, C#, Python, C++, C

[Frameworks/Libraries] Node, Angular, ¡Query, Meteor, Android, SCSS, LESS, ASP.NET MVC

[Databases] MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite, T-SQL

[Tools] Git, Bower, Grunt, Gulp, Bash

## Experience

## ► Write of Passage [Freelance Web Developer]

May 2015 - now

- Working with designer to build a complete web application for a startup using the MEAN stack
- Implementing core features of the platform such as essay delivery from and to end users

## ► Ten Thousand Coffees [Software Engineering Intern]

January 2015 - May 2015

- Improved user retention on platform by using Mandrill for transactional and digest emails with Segment.io for analytics tracking
- Made email verification architecture stateless by switching manually generated bcrypt verification tokens to JWT
- Redesigned the entire messaging system to support multiple participants and an user-friendly scheduling system that was pushed to production
- Added internationalization support for the entire application with angular-translate

#### ► Objectifi [Software Developer]

April 2014 - August 2014

- Enhanced robustness of financial software used by major banking corporations worldwide by fixing database and UI defects
- Wrote E2E regression tests with a web interface that allowed company employees to configure and run tests on different staging environments with real-time logs
- Improved company workflow by over 30% by automating daily tasks such server updates, builds, maintenance, and server monitoring

## **Projects**

► Chidori April 2015 - now

- A cross platform Yugioh client where players can duel against one another online
- Built with Electron, Sass, Bourbon, Neat, and MySQL

► Hearthnet January 2015 - now

- A social platform for Hearthstone players to find other players with similar preferences
- Built with Meteor, Sass, Bourbon, Neat, and MongoDB

► Rallly March 2015 - May 2015

- Implemented time-specific event scheduling to a collaborative scheduling web application
- Built with Node, Express, Angular, MongoDB, SCSS with Bourbon/Neat, and Moment.js

- Feature-rich badminton club management software for Windows that features a members database, asynchronous court timers, and a queuing system
- Built with WPF, C#, .NET 4.0, XAML, Blend

## Hackathons

- ▶ lookup @NASA SpaceApps 2015 #Best Pebble Hack Award #Honourable Mention
  - Built an iOS app that notifies users about the latest transient events based on VOEvents and webscraping, with Pebble support
  - Used Objective C, Pebble SDK, Express, Cheerio.js
- ▶ amusement @HackWestern 2015 #Best Muse Hack Award
  - A mobile web application that keeps users in a calm state by analyzing their EEG activity and playing music from their Spotify playlists correspondingly
  - Used Angular, Express, Spotify API, Muse SDK
- ► vreq @EngHack 2014
  - A visualization of course pre-requisites given a certain course at the University of Waterloo
  - Used D3.js, jQuery, UWaterloo Open Data API
- ▶ favors @Hack the North 2014
  - A platform for exchanging favors with people online and a social experiment to determine the standardized worth of a favor
  - Used Python with Flask, Java with Android SDK, Facebook SDK, MySQL

#### Education

#### ▶ University of Waterloo

September 2013 - May 2018

Candidate for Bachelor of Software Engineering

#### **Awards**

- **2015** Honourable Mention and Best Pebble Hack at NASA SpaceApps
- 2015 Best Muse Hack at HackWestern
- 2014 Dean's Honours List at University of Waterloo
- 2013 President's Scholarship at University of Waterloo
- **2011** HB Blizzard Computer Science Award
- 2010 Top 64 in Junior Canadian Computing Competition Stage 1

#### Interests

I **learn** about web, data science and algorithms. I **play** badminton, ping pong, Hearthstone, and Fire Emblem. I **love** tacos, manga, anime, and bubble tea.